A Guide to the Charles Blair Tavenner Collection, 1709-1980
Thomas Balch Library
Thomas Balch Library
Charles Blair Tavenner Collection 1709-1980
Thomas Balch Library
M 090, OM 020
The collection consists of photocopies of Tavenner's genealogical and research notes. The first three boxes contain his handwritten genealogies of known white adults in Loudoun County prior to 1900. Each box includes an introduction to Tavenner's research and a list of abbreviations he often used. The collection also includes handwritten abstracts of Fairfax, Loudoun, and Prince William County deeds, photocopies of land grants from the areas of the Northern Neck that eventually became Loudoun County, and plats Tavenner created from information in deeds, patents, and grants.
Charles Blair Tavenner, Purcellville, VA.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open for research.
Acquisition Information
Estate of Phronie Tavenner, Purcellville, VA.
Alternative Form Available
None.
Accruals
1995.0004
Biographical Information
Charles Blair Tavenner (1900-1980) was born in Paeonian Springs and spent his childhood in Loudoun County. He graduated from the University of Virginia in 1921 with a BS in Chemistry. Tavenner went on to become a journalist and lived in New York City while employed as managing editor for the periodical Railway Age. After his retirement Tavenner returned to Loudoun County. He spent much of his retirement researching genealogy and local history in Loudoun County.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of photocopies of Tavenner's genealogical and research notes. The first three boxes contain his handwritten genealogies of known white adults in Loudoun County prior to 1900. Each box includes an introduction to Tavenner's research and a list of abbreviations he often used. The collection also includes handwritten abstracts of Fairfax, Loudoun, and Prince William County deeds, photocopies of land grants from the areas of the Northern Neck that eventually became Loudoun County, and plats Tavenner created from information in deeds, patents, and grants.
Arrangement
Box: folder
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Bibliography
"C. Blair Tavenner, 80," Loudoun Times-Mirror, 18 December 1980.
Charles Blair Tavenner Collection, 1709-1980 (M 090), Thomas Balch Library, Leesburg, VA.
Corks and Curls. Charlottesville, VA: The Fraternities and Literary Societies, University of Virginia, 1921.
"A Guide to the Tavenner Genealogical Collection, ca. 1918-1986." Accession Number 11151. Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library.
Location of Originals
University of Virginia Library
Other Finding Aid
None
Technical Requirements
None
Related Material
None
Contents List
  - (Box 1: Loudoun County Genealogies)
    - Abbott-Ayers
    - Baber-Beans
    - Bear-Bitzer
    - Black-Broughton
    - Broun-Carruthers
    - Carson-Clyce
    - Cochran-Cowart
    - Cowden-David
    - Davidson-Dowling
    - Downey-Elderkin
    - Elgin-Ewing
    - Fairfax-Freilinger
    - French-Gideon
  - (Box 2: Loudoun County Genealogies)
    - Gilbert-Grenata
    - Griffith-Harper
    - Harrington-Hill
    - Hilliard-Huff
    - Huffer-Janney
    - Jared-Kyle
    - Lacey-Lindquist
    - Lindsay-McDaniel
    - McDavid-Mayo
    - Mays-Monroe
    - Montieth-Nett
    - Neighbors-Osburn
  - (Box 3: Loudoun County Genealogies)
    - Osler-Pickett
    - Pidgeon-Pyott
    - Quee-Robinson
    - Rodeffer-Schutte
    - Scofield-Slye
    - Smale-Stonebraker
    - Stoneburner-Todd
    - Tolston-Vandevanter
    - Vandiver-Werking
    - Werner-Wolford
    - Wood-Zoll
  - (Box 4)
    - Fairfax County Deed Abstracts, Books A-D, 1742-1757
    - Loudoun County Deed Abstracts, 1757-1826
    - Loudoun County Deed Abstracts, 1757-1826
    - Loudoun County Deed Abstracts, 1757-1826
    - Loudoun County Deed Abstracts, 1757-1826
    - Loudoun County Deed Abstracts, 1757-1826
  - (Box 5)
    - Loudoun County Land Patent Abstracts
    - Loudoun County Order Books, Abstracts of Books A-F, 1758-1776
    - Loudoun County Plats
    - Loudoun County Tithables Abstracts, 1775
    - Miscellaneous Deed Abstracts
    - Northern Neck Land Grants, Plats, and Sketches, vol. 1
    - Northern Neck Land Grants, Plats, and Sketches, vol. 1
    - Northern Neck Land Grants, Plats, and Sketches, vol. 2
    - Northern Neck Land Grants, Plats, and Sketches, vol. 3
  - (Box 6)
    - Prince William County Deed Book Abstracts, 1732-1742
    - Research Articles
    - Research Notes
  - (Box 1)
    - Northern Neck Land Grants, 1709-1791